asungur.com

## sunguralican@gmail.com

22C Oxford Road London, N4 3EY

I am a full-stack software developer based in London.

I believe in writing clean, readable code with comprehensive documentation.

I have multiple years of experience developing full stack applications and back-end development projects using Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript and React, Git, Linux and RESTful APIs.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Full-stack Web Developer, Self-employed

2019 - Present

- Developed web applications using Ruby, Node.js, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Rails, React.js
- Community contributions through building open source projects and blog writing.

#### Trend-check

- https://github.com/asungur/trend\_check
- · A dashboard application retrieves and visualizes the top Twitter trends in the UK.
- Demo: https://trend-check-w-db.herokuapp.com/
- Stack: Ruby, Sinatra, TwitterAPI, GoogleCharts, HTML, CSS

#### Post-it

- https://github.com/asungur/post\_it
- · A Reddit-like application with discussions and upvoting features.
- · Stack: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap

### Hop-timer

- https://github.com/asungur/hop\_timer
- · A Benchmarking Ruby gem that uses check points and evaluates runtime

Academic Consultant 2016 - Present

- · Oxford Brookes University and AA School of Architecture
- Taught procedural modelling, geometry rationalisation, digital fabrication and environmental/structural analysis techniques to MArch and MSc students
- · Projects and academic publications have been awarded nationally and internationally.

#### **Computational Design Consultant**

2017 - Present

- · WilkinsonEyre and Pattern Design Transport and Stadia Projects
- · Developed Dynamo and Grasshopper3D scripts to be used for internal team activities
- Built tools for BIM model transfers, scheduling, clash detection using Python and C# script and RhinoSDK/RevitAPI.
- · Activities reported to the Government R&D Tax Relief programme successfully.
- Have done geometrical rationalisation of doubly/singly curved geometry for structural and environmental efficiencies. Achieved significant cost saving for on budget delivery.
- Project coordination with different engineering disciplines and manufacturers.

## **EDUCATION**

Launch School Remote | 2019-2020

Multi-year full-stack Software Engineering curriculum Ruby, Node.js, HTTP, PostgreSQL | HTML, CSS, JavaScript https://launchschool.com/employers

## **Architectural Association School of Architecture**

London | 2014-2016

Master of Architecture, Distinction, Emergent Technologies & Design

### Middle East Technical University

Ankara | 2009-2014

**Bachelor of Architecture** 

# **SKILLS**

**Languages** Ruby, SQL, Node.js, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Python,

**Frameworks** Erb, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, React.js, Redux,

**Technologies** Git/Github, HTTP, PostgreSQL, Redis, REST APIs,